瞧 要打死一个狗娘养的
See, to cap a motherfucker,
你得拿一把枪指着他的脑袋 然后说 "砰" 接着他就进太平间了
you put a pistol to his head, say, "pow," and he tagged.
- 但Chris那伙人这么干的时候 - 喂 不是这样的 不是的
- But when Chris and them do it-- - Yo, it ain't working, Na'.
- 我知道你在瞎扯 - 用我老妈的名义发誓 Lex没死
- I know you making this up. - Word to my mother, yo. Lex ain't dead.
我昨晚瞧见他在操场旁边的小道里游荡
I seen him creeping in an alley last night near the playground.
大家都知道Lex死了
Everybody know Lex is dead.
不 有的人死了  有的人说是死了其实没死
Nah, there's dead, and there's special dead.
对 Chris平时装神弄鬼的
Yeah, Chris working that juju shit.
不 我是说 他们是僵尸
Nah, man, what I'm saying is they zombies.
要不然他带他们去空地干嘛呢 他需要时间来转化他们
Why you think he take them into vacants? He need time to change them.
信不信随你
You don't believe me, yo, it's on you.
这事情挺好笑的 是不是 Michael?
Yo, they funnin', ain't they, Michael?
我是不懂求神拜佛那一套 但是Chris
I don't know about that voodoo shit, man, but Chris
绝对是在打什么坏主意 带黑人去那里
is definitely doing something-- get a nigger to walk up in there
他和枪击肯定有关
knowing he about to get capped, man.
Chris 他和别人不一样 你看看他们这黑佬穿的衣服就知道了
Chris,he different.u can tell by them coonass country clothes that nigger be wearing.
九毫米的?
Nine?
不是 噪音太大了
Nah, too much bark.
应该是把40-Cal
Probably a.40-cal.
是啊 兄弟们 这可是正经生意
Yeah, man, this is serious business.
那么你是说Lex现在是僵尸吗
So you saying Lex is a zombie?
Pookie Byron 还有所有的黑佬都是
Pookie, Byron, all them niggers.
- 那Chris呢 - 是啊 Chris 僵尸老大
- And Chris? - Yeah, Chris-- Zombie Master.
我就知道这事没完
I knew this wasn't going away.
所以我们才告诉你 Chris势力大着呢
That's what we've been trying to tell you, yo. Chris got the power.
他叫他们来 他们不来也得来
He tell them to come, and they gotta come--
就好象小鬼跟着阎王
Iike the devil do with the damned.
你觉得Chris叫他们干什么呢
What you think Chris got them doing?
他们说不定是间谍
They're probably spies, man.
不然Marlo不会知道这么多事情
Can't figure any other way Marlo knows so much.
对 就是这样 就好像电影"僵尸杀手"什么的一样
Yeah, that's what it is. Like in this movie, "Zombie Killer" or something.
他们夜间出没 猎杀人命
They came out at night, hunting.
- 猎杀人命? - 对 兄弟 他们...
- Hunting? - Yeah, man. They--
对 电影里僵尸把人抓起来
Yeah, and in that movie they was snatching people up,
汲取他们的温暖
stealing their warmth.
火线重案组 第四季 第5集
the.wire.s04e05
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* you gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* keep the devil *
如果你跟我们一起 那就是一起了   -Chris Partlow
圣犹大 败局之救赎者
St. Jude, patron of lost causes.
千万别告诉我你每天夜里
Tell me you ain't been on bended knee
在闭上眼睛之前
whispering in his saintly ear each and every night
都向他那圣洁之耳祷告
before you close those peepers.
我就知道你肯定这么干了 Tommy 居然抓到了这么个漏洞
I know you have, Tommy, catch a break like this.
Stan 你确定吗
Stan, you're sure about this?
用我母亲的灵魂起誓 绝对错不了
On my mother's soul. It's a lock.
指派一个新人 一个女人 来做首席警探
Assigned a rookie-- a broad, no less--as lead detective.
还把一个好手给撤下来了 我听说
Pulled a good man off, too, I heard.
Tom Tommy 记住
Tom.Tommy, remember--
我随时效劳
anything you need.
他也真有点本事
He's a piece of work.
Valchek? 他可是带着领地来的
Valchek? Comes with the territory.
你要是想坐上首席区议员的座位
You want the First District council seat,
你就得同他们丢在东南区的
you make nice with whatever Polish or Greek commander
- 波兰或者希腊帮的头目搞好关系 - 原来不是意大利籍
- they dump in the southeast. - Not ltalian.
不 那儿没有多少我们的人了
No, there ain't enough of us left down there.
- 你觉得他的消息准么 - Royce搅和案子的事情吗
- You think he has this right? - That Royce tampered with the case?
市长不可能知道
No way the mayor knows.
没错 这事肯定全是Ervin Burrell经手的
You're right. This one has Ervin Burrell written all over it.
不管市长知不知道 如果这是真的
Fuck if the mayor knows or not. If it's true,
我们就放风出去 好好给他们一击
we get it out there quick and bang him hard.
- 我来公开吗 - 他们决无还手之力
- I go public? - They can't spin this.
他们插手刑事案件
They sabotaged a criminal case.
没有那个实力 我们就无法控制情况的走向
No spin on a knuckleball, you still can't tell how it's gonna break.
我们把这事告诉Tony Gray 自己不要参与其中
We feed it to Tony Gray. We keep ourselves out of the line of fire,
戳痛Royce的同时 再给他们加一个彩蛋
sting Royce, and as an added bonus,
打压市长的同时 给Gray的竞选团也鼓鼓劲
give Gray's campaign a boost which comes at the expense of the mayor's base.
我状态起来了之后 也是个阴狠的角色
I'm a devious motherfucker once I get going.
总而言之
So all told,
我们需要在6处逮捕13名嫌疑人
we're looking at 13 warrants and six locations.
从我手上的人手来看...
And given my staffing situation...
没问题
Not a problem.
我可以把毒检部 FLEX  还有公共安全小组都分给你
I can give you my D.E.U., Flex, and Ops squads.
- 如果需要 可以再分一点警员 - 太好了
- A sector of uniforms if you need it. - Great.
问题是 你这是将窃听情报 浪费在街头逮捕中
The problem is, you're wasting a wiretap on street-level arrests.
这些突袭是有意义的 我们说不定能抓到Marlo
We do these raids right, we might catch Marlo
或者在这几个地方逮到他手下的头目
or one of his lieutenants at one of these locations,
- 和毒品一起人赃俱获 - Marlo Stanfield
- get them with dope on the table. - Marlo Stanfield--
在房子里 人赃俱获?
in a room, with dope on the table?
我以前还突袭过比他更厉害的人
I've kicked down doors and surprised bigger players than him.
好吧 但我得警告你 警督
Well, let me warn you, Lieutenant--
我可不打算为了些小混混 就用上窃听装置
I am not about to litigate a wiretap for a handful of street rips.
好吧 随你 检察官
Well... that's on you, Counselor.
不 才不是
No, it's not.
警长 明天见
Major, see you tomorrow.
浮尸 你这儿还有么
Floaters-- you had any more?
- 这个季节不太多 - 那腐尸呢
- No more than usual for the season. - What about decomps?
停尸间里有么
What do you got in the decomp room?
- 两三个无名的 - 巴尔的摩发现的吗
- Two or three unidentifieds. - Found in Baltimore?
不 两个是Prince George的
No. Actually, two from Prince George's,
- 一个是多尔切斯特的 - 不 他不会去那么远的地方
- one from Dorchester. - Nah, he wouldn't drive that far.
我先把话说明白了
Let me get this straight:
你们在找一具尸体 别的都不要
You're looking for extra bodies, no one in particular,
只要那个你们已经用窃听锁定的孩子?
other than this one kid you already put out on the teletype.
对 没错
Yeah. You on it.
你们闲得没事干了吗
You fellas don't have enough work?
如果你们上课做练习 回家做作业 那么就有一个小标签
If you do your classwork, homework,you earn stickers.
要命呀 你天天变来变去的
Dag, yo, every day you be changing it up.
你可把我们搞糊涂了 P先生
You got us confused, Mr. P.
上课表现好 还有一个小标签
Behave in class, that's another sticker.
每周结束的时候  标签数量前四的可以得到奖励
At the end of the week, the four with the most stickers get a prize
然后可以在月底去参加狂欢节
and are eligible for a grand drawing at the end of the month.
不做作业的
Don't do your work,
上课表现不好的
misbehave in class...
我会把你的名字写在这里
...your name goes here.
留校惩罚 放学后一小时 决不姑息
Detention-- a full hour after school, no exceptions.
所以决定权在你们 是要奖励小标签
So it's up to you-- stickers for prizes
还是要放学和我杵在一起
or stay with me after school.
喂 P先生 你干嘛惩罚我呢
Yo, Mr. P., why you do me detention, huh?
你在课堂上插话了 Namond
You interrupted the class, Namond.
唉 你刚来的时候 对我们都挺正派的
Yo, when you first came in here, you was all treating us straight up,
现在我还不知道规则 你就先坑我了
and now you just dog me before I even know the rules.
这可不对 兄弟
That ain't right, man.
你说的没错 Namond
When you're right, Namond, you're right.
嘿 P先生 我想要点小标签
Hey, Mr. P., I want me some of them stickers.
Zenobia 你得先做作业
Zenobia, you have to do your work.
我也想啊 但我没笔
I want to, but I ain't got no pencils.
我才不要施舍来的笔呢
I don't want no damn welfare pencil!
在我看来
It seems to me
这里可以分为两种学生
there are two kinds of kids walking in this building--
自贬的孩子 和角落里的孩子
stoop kids and corner kids.
- 什么意思? - 自贬的孩子就是
- Excuse me? - You know, stoop kids
当他们父母要求的时候 他们还会继续进步
stay on their front steps when their parents tell them.
而其他的一些则退到角落里去了
The others go down to the corners.
他们在教室里坐不牢 而其他孩子可以
They can't sit still in the class. The others can and do.
- 所以得把他们分开 - 这是区分对待
- So separate the two. - That's tracking.
- 什么 - 区分学生
- Excuse me? - Tracking students.
这是教育界里的黑话
It's a nasty phrase in educational circles.
是指对孩子分别寄予不同的期望
It refers to the grouping of children based on expected performance.
- 这又怎么了 - 如果你降低对某些学生的期望
- What's wrong with it? - It says you have reduced expectations
那你对他们的学习成绩 就不那么看重了
for certain students, that you expect less from them academically.
所以你假装自己在教这些孩子
So you pretend to teach all these kids,
但其实你一个都不愿意教
and the truth is, you ain't teaching any of them.
但如果没了干扰
But what if the stoop kids
那些自贬的孩子就可以留在课堂中呢
could be in classrooms where there was no disruptions?
- 那角落孩子怎么办 - 你就是为了他们来的 对不对
- And the corner kids? - They're the ones you're after, right?
你就是因为这个才能挣大钱
That's why you got the grant money.
只要不包括仓库区来的孩子
As long as this doesn't involve warehousing children,
一切对我工作有利的  我都会支持
I'm for anything that allows me to do my job.
这里的老师都会这么回答你
Every teacher here will tell you the same.
你的责任则是设计出一个计划
The trick for you is to come up with a program
能够帮助这些角落孩子
that actually addresses itself to the corner kids.
我们将某些孩子从普通班隔离开 他们不会感觉难堪吗
We start pulling kids out of regular classes-- won't they be stigmatized?
难道每天从教室里被赶出来 就不难堪吗
There's not a stigma in being booted out of class every other day?
问题是
Question is,
我们怎么才能区别出角落孩子
how do we identify the corner kids?
这不是问题
That won't be a problem.
好吧 好吧
Okay. Okay.
你知道题目讲什么吗
You understand the work?
别这样 很简单的 我知道你做得出
Come on, this is easy. I know you can do it.
你逼我给你留校惩罚
You're not giving me a choice. You have detention.
哇 D女士在摇树丛
Yo, Na', Mrs. D. shaking bushes.
回座位去
Back to your seats.
搞什么呐 她把我的刀拿走了
What the fuck? She got my blade, yo.
我说了 都回座位去
I said, "Back to your seats."
D女士这个小偷
Yo, Mrs. D. be stealing shit.
我这辈子都拿不回我的刀了
I ain't never gonna get my blade back.
喂 你看着我干什么呢  我作业不是做了吗
Yo, what are you all up on me for? I do my work.
我不是"喂" 给我看你的作业
I'm not your yo. Show me your work.
是啊 做了
Yeah, I see.
喂 我写字写得手疼 你泰诺有么
Yo, my hand hurting from all this learning. You got some Tylenol?
我这儿有惩罚
What I got for you is detention.
- 操你大爷的 Prezbo - 哦哦哦
- You know what? Fuck you, Prezbo. - Oh-hh!
操你这个狗杂种
Fucking gimpy-assed, big-grill motherfucker.
够了 出去!
That's it. You're out of here!
滚啊!
Go!
把你那警棍拿出来抽我呀
Get your police stick out your desk and beat me.
- 你自己知道你想抽我 - 哦哦哦
- You know you fucking want to. - Oh-hh.
瞧什么瞧呢 臭婊子
The fuck you looking at, bitch?
哦 Sampson女士 我...
Oh-hh, Ms. Sampson, l--
Namond Brice  如果你刚不打算去校长室
Namond Brice, if you weren't headed to the main office,
- 你现在可以去了 - 对 我这就...
- you are now. - Yeah, I was just--
这就是角落孩子吗
One of the corner kids, huh?
对 你需要的时候 他们就会出现的 不是么
Yeah, they do step up when you need them, don't they?
怎么 你想让我说你没错吗 你没错
Look, what? You want me to say you right? You right.
上次打牌我是该派点人看着
I should have had protection at the card game.
过去就过去了
Done is done.
我们现在该想想 拿Omar怎么办
Now we need to decide what we're gonna do about Omar.
你价钱开的对
You make the price right,
总有人会替你把那家伙给你收拾了
somebody gonna get a whiff of that bushwhacker's ass.
到那时候你再想吧
Now you take it from there.
你觉得这样行吗
You think so?
我不是说搞不定Omar 是个黑佬都能搞定
I ain't saying Omar can't be got. Any nigger can be got.
但如果我们放话出去了
But once we put word to ear
他知道我们想要买人搞他
and he learn that we pricing out his head,
他肯定要跟我们搞他一样来搞我们
he's gonna be trying us like we're trying him.
- 那你是说这次算了? - 不
- You saying I should let it slide? - Nah.
不 我们换个方法来搞他
Nah, we get at him another way,
不要买人 不要用这种方法
get at him without no bounties, no bullshit like that.
Barksdale把这地方搞得天翻地覆 想要抓到他
Barksdale turned this town upside down hunting him,
但他结果还是软掉了
and all he ended up looking was weak.
我可不是Barksdale
I ain't no Barksdale.
我只是想说 光说没用
I'm just saying talk is cheap.
我们稳住了  总能想到办法把这黑佬给搞了
We sit on it, we gonna figure out a way to get that faggot.
但事成之前 不要到处宣扬
But till then we don't say a mumbling word.
我现在有6块了  我到时候再还你4块 成不成
I got me six now, and I'll give you the four later, all right? Come on!
- 不行 我现在就要这10块 - Sherrod!
- Nah. I'm gonna need the whole 10 now. - Sherrod!
- 今天不上课吗 - 半天放假 老师开会
- You ain't in school? - I'm half a day-- teachers' meeting.
得了吧 我跟你说过 扯谎也扯高明点
Come on, I told you about those lame excuses, man.
- 我先跟他说话的 - 不用拉拉扯扯的
- I was talking to him first. - Ain't no need for physical contact--
你有4块吗 我还差4块
You got $4 for me? I'm short $4.
你他妈在说什么呢
What the fuck are you talking--
吐什么脏呢 黑佬 你身上有多少钱
Got a cart full of shit, nigger. What you got for me?
我知道你藏着
I know you holding.
藏哪里了 你聋了吗
Where's it at? You ain't hear?
在我鞋子里 在我鞋子里
Okay.It's in my shoe-- my shoe.
现在不差钱了 小子
Don't need the four now, son.
该死 喂 铲子在哪儿 快把这黑佬给埋了
Damn, yo, where the shovel at? Bury that nigger, man.
给你先生 谢谢
Here you go, sir, thank you.
- Tommy Carcetti 竞选市长 - 祝你好运 Tommy
- Tommy Carcetti, running for mayor. - Good luck, Tommy.
- 嘿 Carcetti先生 我投票给你 - 谢谢
- Hey, Mr. Carcetti, you got my vote. - Thanks.
- Tom Carcetti - 非常感谢
- Tom Carcetti. - Hey, thank you very much.
你好 Tommy Carcetti 竞选市长
How you doing? Tommy Carcetti, running for mayor.
好了 议员 该去西市区了
Okay, Councilman, time to hit the West Side.
算你狠
Pretty motherfucker--
逼我玩真的
he's gonna make me go to my game face.
好的 我要25盒蜂蜜牛奶球
Okay, I'll take 25 of the honeysuckle incense cones--
这些能够保证我下周营养充沛
they'll keep me healthy for next week.
- Tommy! - 失陪
- Tommy! - Excuse me.
Tony Gray的人说20分钟后在他的办公室见
Tony Gray's people say 20 minutes at their place.
该死 Clarence 看上去就好象你年轻了十岁
Shit, Clarence. Look like you did in '98
那时候你可是让所有人都大吃一惊
when you surprised the hell out of everyone.
都放马过来吧
Just bring 'em on.
为什么把这事透给我们 你们为什么不自己去搞垮Royce?
Why give it to us? Why don't you stick it to Royce yourself?
因为在辩论赛之后
Because after what Tommy did at the debate,
从我口里说出去 同从Tommy口里说出去没什么差别
it'll seem like more of the same if it comes from him.
而如果我们用这消息 抢到了Royce4到5个点的支持率
And if we use it to take four or five points out of Royce's base,
对他来说一样也有帮助
it helps him as much as us.
一石二鸟
Once bitten, twice shy.
同Tommy Caretti竞争 我总得把棋都想好了
With Tommy Carcetti, I got to always think a step ahead.
你瞧 Tony 你赢不了的 唯一的问题是
Look, Tony, you ain't gonna win. So the only question is
你是输在24个点还是28个点
whether you wanna lose with 24% of the vote or 28%.
把支持率提上去了
You bring the numbers up,
在议会里你脸面也过得去
you look good for the legislature--
说不定你能参选国会
maybe a congressional run.
- Albert Stokes - 到
- Albert Stokes. - Here.
P先生 我能走了吗 我妈妈让我一放学就回家
Mr. P., can I go? My moms told me to go straight home after school.
我妈妈也这么说
Mine too.
你把墨水倒在我桌上的时候 怎么没有想想你妈妈呢
You should have thought of that before you smeared ink all over my desk.
又不是我的错 我的笔漏了
Weren't my fault. My pen exploded.
Michael
Michael.
Michael Lee?
P先生 求你了 我能走了吗
Mr. P., please, can I go?
我都没有吃午饭 我的肚子一直在叫
I ain't eat no lunch, and my stomach making all these noises.
我发誓再也不会把你的笔弄地上了
Look, I won't ever disrespect your pencil again, I promise.
Zenobia 不是因为笔
Zenobia, it wasn't about the pencil.
求你了 P先生
Please, Mr. P.
- 好吧 好了 安静 - 安静
- Okay okay, all right. - All right.
就这一次例外
Just this one time, I'll make an exception.
但下次 一个小时谁都别想跑
But next time, expect to stay the full hour.
- 你来这里做什么 - 来道歉
- Why are you here? - Came to say sorry.
我不是故意吐你一脸脏的
I didn't mean to get all up in your face like that.
我接受道歉 Namond
I appreciate that, Namond.
承认错误需要勇气
It takes courage to admit when you're wrong.
我不能理解的是 我见过你 在Sampson女士的课堂上认真做作业
What I can't understand-- I've seen you in Ms. Sampson's class doing your work.
- 你为什么不能在我的课上也这样呢 - 我想的  真的
- Why can't you do the same in here? - I mean to, I do.
但是我心底里有个小恶魔 我有时控制不了自己就爆发了
It's just the evil get in me and before I know it, I go off.
好吧
Well...
我们看看明天有没有改观
tomorrow we'll see if we can do better.
明天不行 D女士把我罚出课堂了
Can't tomorrow. Mrs. D. put me out.
我得走了 回见 P先生
I gotta bump. Later, Mr. P.
你能不能去外面等等...
If you can wait outside...
没事的 他不用出去
It's okay. He can stay.
谢谢
Thank you.
P先生 你知道Michael没法留下来罚校的
Mr. P., you know Michael can't make it to detention.
我知道他没留下来 所以现在加倍了
I know he didn't. Now it's doubled.
- 他得留校两天 - 不 我是说 他不能留校
- He's got two days to serve. - Nah, I mean, he can't.
他得去接他弟弟放学
He got to go pick up his little brother from school.
那他得找其他人替他去了
Well, he'll just have to find somebody else to do that.
不 事情不是这样的
It-- it ain't like that.
我是说 如果他能来 Michael会来的
I mean, Michael would come if he could,
但没有别人能替他接他弟弟Bug
but wouldn't have nobody else to pick up his little brother Bug.
你知道的 他妈妈 在抽那玩意儿
You know, his mother, she on that stuff.
我们走路回家 你一起来么
We walking home. You coming?
哦 不 我在等Alpo Sampson女士把他留校了
Oh, no, I'm waiting on Alpo. Ms. Sampson got him doing detention.
- 那么你要等到5点了 - 对 她很严格
- You gonna be here till, like, 5:00. - Yeah, she a hard lady.
她甚至不让他们打球
She don't ever give a brother no play.
- 行 到时候再见 - 行
- All right. I'll holla at you later. - All right, yo.
那么说你不去NBA?
So you're not gonna be in the NBA?
那你一定是去NFL（橄榄球联盟)咯
Then it must be the NFL?
我还以为班里的男生都会变成职业球员
I thought all the boys in class were gonna join the pros.
没 不过是说说罢了
Nah, that's just something we say.
那你想做什么
So what about you?
你长大之后想做什么
What do you wanna be when you grow up?
我想开一家自己的店
I'm gonna own my own store.
挺聪明的 那你得学好数学
That's smart. You're gonna need to know a lot of math.
你忘在车里了
You left them in there.
- 哦 - 别着急 P先生
- Oh-hh. - Hey, don't worry, Mr. P.
有我们呢 嘿 Donut!
We got you. Hey, Donut!
- 来了 - Donut可爱车了
- Yo, yeah. - Donut's crazy with cars.
他什么车都能撬开
He can open anything.
- 嘿 怎么了 - 嘿
- Hey. What up, man? - Hey.
他把钥匙锁车里了
Yo, he locked his keys in there.
没事的 我可以叫汽车协会的人来
It's okay, I can call AAA.
没事的 老大
Oh, no problem, chief.
你就这么想去街角工作么
Feel the need to work them corners, huh?
我这么问  只是因为你完全没必要这么做
I'm just asking 'cause you don't need to be doing what you're doing.
我得自己去学一点东西
I need to learn some shit on my own.
我想要帮你 Sherrod 但是你这样我没法帮
I'm trying to help you, Sherrod, but you making it so I can't.
我都不认识那个打你的人 Bubs
I didn't even know the man who beat on you, Bubs.
他差了几块钱
He was short money on the corner.
我发誓他跟我没什么关系
I swear he wasn't nothing to me.
对 但真惹祸了你也没法处理 对么
Yeah, but when the shit start, there's nothing to be done, right?
要是他动手打你了我会怎么办
What would I have done if he started whaling on you?
我是不是也和你没有关系 街角这儿就是这样
Same kind of nothing, see? That's how the corners be.
他们都在利用你 Sherrod
They going to use you up, Sherrod.
今晚你还睡这儿吧 但如果你明天早上还不去上学
You welcome to stay tonight, but you ain't in school tomorrow morning,
那我们就此别过吧
this partnership need to be done.
这两个区是第五区的前导
These two precincts are the bellwether for the Fifth.
如果你能在这儿吃掉Carecetti18个点
If you can take even 18% out of Carcetti in these,
那他在全市范围内就拿不到足够的票数
it's a good guess he won't have the numbers citywide.
在那里谁支持我们竞选?
And who are we ticketed with over here?
希望是NDO 因为...
The N.D.O., I hope, because...
这份陈述中显示 数位高位警方官员
...this amid allegations that high-ranking police officials intervened
插手将一位老练的探长 从一起争议案件中调离
to have a veteran police detective removed from the controversial case.
随着Thomas Carcetti议员声称
The Braddock murder became a focal point in the mayoral campaign
西巴尔的摩人Baraddock之所以被谋杀 是因为他是一起案件的证人
when Councilman Thomas Carcetti alleged the West Baltimore man was killed
这起谋杀案便成为了市长竞选中的焦点
because he was a witness in the case.
因为他们担忧 警方将会证实
...Because they were afraid the police would prove
其最为担心的事情 即Fredro Braddock被谋杀的原因
what they most fear, that Fredro Braddock was murdered
是因为他是一名证人 而政府对其保护不周
because he was a witness, and the city failed to protect him.
三个频道都在放
It's on all three channels.
太阳报和邮报都打电话来 让我们做出回应
And "The Sun" and "The Post" are both calling for comment.
我在警局内的线人告诉我 一名资深警官
And my sources within the department say the rank-and-file officers
只为达到无耻政客的目的 而被简单地调离
are simply appalled by this blatant political manipulation.
要死 声音开大点
Damn, turn it up.
嘿 Greggs 你出名了
Hey, Greggs, you're famous.
他们毫无理由地调离了一名声名显赫
...is to remove a highly-decorated veteran
有着十五年谋杀案调查经验的警官
with 15 years' experience as a murder investigator without reason...
- 那是我 - 然后用一个从来没有调查过
- That'd be me. - Then replaced with a rookie
一起谋杀案的新人替而代之
who has yet to handle a single homicide investigation...
- 那是你 -...我们必须来想一想...
- That'd be you. -...then we need to rethink...
我哪儿招惹他了?
The fuck I ever do to him?
你这玩意是不是做得有点重了啊
You gonna make it too heavy, yo.
如果我们再做大点 说不定有用
It might work if we make it bigger.
如果我们用轻木来做 就会有用了
It would work if we had balsa wood, you know?
- 那才是又轻又牢 - 你还真是满嘴瞎...
- It's really light and strong. - Man, you so full of--
哦 该死
oh, shit.
僵尸大师
Zombie Master.
跟我们走走聊聊
Need to take us a little walk.
不 我在这儿挺好的
Nah, I'm good here.
喂 年轻人多动动
Yo. Young'uns need to move along.
好 Chris 我们这就走
Sure, Chris, we'll bump.
- 喂 小混混 你姐姐和我一个班的 - 搞什么?
- Yo, Snoop, your sister in my class. - What the fuck?
你磕高了吗 黑佬
You high or something, nigger?
你们这群小子在抽大烟么
You boys be smoking that shit?
听说了你做的好事
Hearing good things about you.
说你挺直了腰杆 照顾自家人
Say you straight up, take care of your people,
没投降讨饶
not begging no handouts.
小混球 黑佬在跟你说话呢
Motherfucker, you hear the nigger talking to you,
他表扬你呢 你这样站着看上去真傻
giving you praises and shit. You standing here looking fucking stupid.
喂 别说了
Yo, chill.
有时候她是有些火爆
Sometimes she get a little hot.
我只是说这小子不对劲
I'm just saying the boy ain't right!
喂 我们一直在找好兄弟
Yo, we always in the market for a good soldier.
我们找到合适的 就会照顾他
When we see one we like, we take care of the situation--
领他入门 教育他 给他家的感觉
take him in, school him, make him family.
如果你和我们在一起 那我们就把你放心上 兄弟之间互相照应
And if you're with us,you're with us, just like we'd be with you all the way.
你有意思的话 就加入吧
You have a mind, you're in.
听着 兄弟 我有家
Look, man. I already got a family--
我妈妈 还有我弟弟
my moms and my little brother.
对 我听说了
Yeah, heard that.
但你考虑下吧
But think on it.
如果你需要什么 我们会来帮忙的
We'll be around if you need something.
他看到我了 我就知道
He saw me, yo. I knew it.
我知道Chris在问Michael我的事
I knew Chris was asking Michael about me.
我知道 我死定了
I knew it, man. I'm dead.
- 兄弟 谢谢望风了 - 没事
- Yo, man, good looking out. - Yeah.
- 我还以为他们... - 对 我知道 我知道
- I thought they was gonna-- - Yeah, I know, I know.
他问起我什么了 我知道他问到我了
What-what he ask about me? I know he asked about me.
- 你说什么了 你告诉他什么了 - 冷静点
- What'd you say? What'd you tell him? - Calm down,
- 和你没什么关系 - 喂 说真的
- it weren't even about you. - Yo, for real,
你的告诉我 他问你什么了
you need to tell me. What did he ask you?
对 没错 Chris关心死你了
Yo, you right, man. Chris was all up in your business.
你这次真是惹恼了他了
He down on you for some deep shit, man.
我都不知道是什么事
I don't even know what.
没呢 我开你玩笑呢
Nah, I'm just fucking with you, man.
他都没有提起你的名字
He didn't even speak your name.
Erv 接下来怎么办 你的警员要开枪射击旅客么
So, Erv, what's next? Your officers gonna shoot a couple of tourists?
还是朝港口开几架直升机?
Maybe fly a helicopter into Harbor Place?
我的连任竞选都最后一个礼拜了 我还能指望点啥
What can we expect the last week of my re-election campaign?
市长 我按照你说的做了 一分不多 一分不少
Sir, I did what you asked-- no more, no less.
Hamsterdam 合法的毒品区吗
Hamsterdam-- legalized drug zone?
哦 这是他的责任
Oh, he takes responsibility for that.
- 满城都是传票 - 这也是之一
- The subpoenas all over town. - That, too.
还有证人谋杀案的消息泄露 也是他的问题 对么
Well, then the leak about the witness murder. That was his shop too, right?
- 对头 - 还有最后一件
- Hell, yeah. - And now this last thing,
将调查的警员调离案件 这算什么 这算什么?
transferring detectives off the case-- what is that? What is that?
- 干涉调查 - 没错
- Scuttling the investigation. - Yeah, right.
- 对 真糟糕 天啊 - 市长先生 你要我
- Yeah, that's awful-- Jesus! - Mr. Mayor, you asked me
放慢调查的节奏
to slow that investigation down.
个中微妙你能体会么 Ervin
Subtle, Ervin. Hmm?
你能隐瞒几周的证据
You hold a few facts for a few weeks.
将某个报告锁在抽屉里
You put a report or two in a desk drawer.
但你居然把调查的警官调离了案件?!
But the transferring of people off a case?!
你当时告诉我...
Look, you told me...
你特别要求我不要...
you specifically wanted me to not--
Ervin 你可以走了
Ervin, you may leave.
- 市长先生... - 没你的事了 局长
- Mr. Mayor-- - That will be all, Commissioner.
不 我要和你的副局长聊聊 Ervin
No, I need a word or two with your deputy, Ervin.
坐吧
Have a seat.
我想要警告他来着
I tried to warn him.
我是说既然证人被杀的事情已经泄露了
I mean, if it leaked out of Homicide about the dead witness,
那为什么不会泄露 我们调离了警官的事情呢
why wouldn't it leak that we bumped a detective?
你之前为什么没来找我们
Why didn't you come to us beforehand?
我是一个忠诚的下级 市长先生
I'm a loyal subordinate, Mr. Mayor,
Ervin是个好人  就是工作压力有点大
and Ervin is a good man working under considerable pressure.
他是个庸士
He's a hack.
你不觉得压力大么 副局长
You're not bothered by the pressure, Deputy?
一点都不
Not in the least.
我需要你把这事摆平 Bill
I need you to make this go away, Bill.
我不会忘了你的好的 相信我
I won't forget, believe me.
还有一件事 瘦子Charles找上我了
Another thing-- Slim Charles got up with me.
说胖子想要坐下谈谈
Said the fat man want a sitdown.
不行 我已经谈过了
Nah. I did that already.
瘦子说胖子之前就知道 牌局会被端掉
Well, Slim say the fat man knew the card game was gonna get took.
他知道啊  去安排吧
He did, did he? Set it up.
你们为什么总来这里
Why you always be back here?
安静 来什么人我都能看见
Quiet. And I can see what comes.
但这儿风吹雨打的
But you out in the weather and shit.
- 我不喜欢在屋子里谈 - 对
- I don't like to speak in no rooms. - Yeah.
喂 别 你不能久留
Yo, oh-oh, you ain't staying long.
我来告诉你呀 你的钱我快凑齐了
So you know, I almost got that for you.
就是还需要点时间
I just need a couple of days more.
我的钱你先拿着吧
You can keep my money for now.
- 我需要你帮我做点别的事 - 随便什么 Marlo 你说了算
- I got something that needs doing. - Anything, Marlo-- your call.
Omar会来你的店 洗劫你
Omar gonna come in your store, stick it up, rob you.
你要报警 做笔录 懂了吗
You gonna call the police, make a report. You feel me?
对 那行 但是 你知道等他出来了...
Yeah, that'll work, but, uh, you know when he get out,
他会冲着我来的 我不是害怕什么的
he's coming right at me, I ain't scared or nothing.
- 只是提醒下 - 他出不来的
- I'm just saying, you know? - He ain't gonna get out.
抢劫是可以保释的
A man make bail on robbery.
那就别让他保释
Make it no bail.
如果你有麻烦 比如说不能留校 那你得告诉我
If you have a problem,Iike you can't make it to detention,you need to tell me.
那是你的责任
That's your responsibility.
大家都乐意帮助你 但是你不开口别人不知道
People will be more than willing to help you out,but it's up to you to ask.
你回餐厅吧 或者在这儿吃也行
You can go back to the cafeteria...or hang up here.
Duquan 你能过来一下吗
Duquan, could you come here?
你也许可以帮我一个忙 我买多了
I thought maybe you could help me out-- I packed too much.
拿着去餐厅的自动售货机上买点饮料吧
Take this down to the cafeteria and get yourself something to drink from the machine.
谢谢
Thank you.
Crystal 你有空吗
Crystal, you got a second?
Duquan怎么了
What's up with Duquan?
我给了他一点新衣服 我还以为...
I gave him some new clothes. I was expecting--
他说不定已经弄丢了
He might have lost them.
这么快?
That fast?
不是这样的
It weren't that.
他那儿的人拿走他的衣服 在街角卖
His people take his clothes, sell it on the corners.
- 不是真的吧 - 是真的 老师
- You're kidding. - No, sir.
大家都知道
Everybody knows.
接下来我就要说到我们的解决方案
Which brings me to what we're proposing--
对不同的孩子 使用不同的方法
different kids, different approaches.
你告诉我们都要去找些什么人征求许可
You tell us who we need to touch at North Avenue to get the go-ahead.
那迷宫吗
The "Puzzle Palace"?
听着 如果你们还想继续搅和进来帮忙 我是没什么意见
Look, if y'all still wanna jump in and help, I'm fine with it.
在我这里 这一句话就够了
That's about all the okay you need in my house.
Stricker街的那事儿 在你办公室里等着你去解决呢
The Stricker Street situation is waiting in the office.
芝麻大点事情闹得天翻地覆
Neighborhood squabbles, and my babies bring it in here.
昨天打了两次 都是因为做妈的合不来
Two fights yesterday-- all because the mothers can't get along.
我得走了
I gotta go.
Donnelly夫人会给你们讲细节的
Mrs. Donnelly will work out the nuts and bolts.
但正如我刚所说的 谢谢
But just so you hear it, thank you.
体制里的别人可不会再说这样的话了
It'll be the only time anyone in this system will think to say it.
他是个好人 你们得保护他
He's a good man. You need to protect him.
- 保护他? - Withers校长
- Protect him? - Principal Withers
义无反顾地支持你们
just went out on a limb for you,
而这个体制里的人都知道拿谁开刀
and in this system they know how to handle a chainsaw.
怎么了
Excuse me?
要是有人对我们的所作所为不满 就会怪到他的头上
Anyone has a problem with what we're doing, it's on him.
你们要看八年级学生吗
So you specified eighth-graders?
我们有256名在读
We have 256 on roll.
241名参加的是常规课程
241 attend on a regular basis.
这些中有40个孩子 符合你们所谓的角落孩子
Of those, 40 or so would fit your bill of corner kids.
40?
还成
Pretty workable.
- 你觉得呢 - 先从10个左右开始吧
- What would you suggest? - Start with 10 or so.
Sampson夫人那儿的足够你们应付了
Ms. Sampson has enough to get you going.
- 其中一个叫Namond Brice? - 祸害中的祸害
- One of them named Namond Brice? - Pick of the litter.
但你们得等  他正在接受3天的留校处分
But you'll have to wait. He's on a three-day suspension.
Tilghman高中 有什么可以为您效劳的?
Tilghman Middle School. Can I help you?
记得当年我还是个实习警察 我来这儿找一具尸体
Remember when I was a cadet, I was up here on a cadaver search.
老师在电台里说
Instructor gets on the radio to say,
"我们在找一具特定的尸体"
"We're looking for one body in particular.
"如果你碰上一具就瞧个半天 我们一天就费在这儿了"他说
If you go grabbing everyone you see, we'll be here all day," he says.
Leakin公园...
Leakin Park...
西巴尔的摩人的葬身之地
where West Baltimore brings out its dead.
现在看来 不再是了
Not anymore, from the look of things.
至少路边不是了
Not by the roadside, anyway.
如果他把尸体扔在这里 他会扔到树林深处去
If he's dumping them here, he's dumping them deep in the woods.
走吧
Come on.
预计在每一个突击点
At each raid site,
我们都能够找到毒品 赃款 或者枪支
we're anticipating dope or cash or guns.
逮捕令是留待重要的地点使用的
All warrants are for prime locations
在那里我们将找到高级别的犯罪者
Iinked to high-level violators.
过期的地址只能找到底层的跑腿小子
Weeks-old addresses linked to low-level corner boys.
同时我们将在这些地点扫荡毒品巢穴
We'll also be sweeping drug corners at these locations.
车会停在这些地方
Wagons will hold in this location here.
突袭时间 下午三点整
Jump-off time-- 1500 hours.
我们在行动前10分钟到达指定位置
We take our position 10 minutes before the assault here.
听我的命令行动
The go is on my say-so.
还有问题吗 很好
Questions? Excellent.
在行动开始之前  我们都留在娱乐室待命
We'll hold in the rec room till it's time to stage.
逮捕令是一件事
Warrants are one thing,
但扫荡Marlo Stanfield的人手? 你们说真的吗
but street sweeps on Marlo Stanfield's crews? Are you guys serious?
Carv 你太把这些屁话当一回事了
Carv, you give these hoodleheads too much credit.
相信我 好奇宝宝
Trust me on this, Boy Wonder.
当我没说
Never mind this horseshit.
他们给你都安排了什么工作
So what've they got you doing for your man?
谁 警督吗
Who, the lieutenant?
不是 是Royce  Herc 市长是你的饭票啊
No, Royce. Herc, the mayor's your meal ticket.
他连任四年 你就可以带上金穗带了
He gets another four years, you're liable to wear the gold braid.
难道你不出去给他摇旗呐喊吗
Shouldn't you be out waving a campaign sign or some shit?
于是乎重案调查小队的命运 就以一声呜呼完结
And so ends the last crusade of the Major Crimes Unit--with a whimper.
Lester看到自己的窃听器 为了这样的蠢事而被拆掉 肯定会哭
Lester would cry to see his wiretap cannibalized for that crap.
扫荡Marlo Stanfield?
Street sweeps on Marlo Stanfield?
- 你手上还有什么案子吗 - 毒品的案子?
- So what else you got cooking? - Narcotics cases?
刑事调查局的人拿到了缅甸人的公诉书 没什么会漏过去的了
C.I.D. has the Burman indictment coming in. Nothing past that.
随着事情的发展 看来毒品的关联越来越弱了
As wars go, this drug thing seems to rate less and less.
如果Demper胜诉了  并且试着忘记我干涉的事情
If Demper wins and manages to forgive my trespasses,
也许我还能去求点别的什么
maybe I'll go in and beg for something new.
我也不知道 只是感觉受够了
I don't know. Just feels like enough's enough.
Crutchfield 二号线 打进
Crutchfield, line two, lntake.
- 警长 你找我? - 对
- Sergeant, you were looking for me? - I was, yeah.
咖喱薯条? 小鸡块?
Curly fry? Chicken doohickey?
坐下
Sit down.
Norris重回Braddock的案子
Norris is back on the Braddock case.
是副局长的命令
It's by order of the deputy ops.
其实 我们要这么说
In fact, we're gonna go with a story that says
他从来都没有调离过这个案子 你们俩是在一起搭档
he was never off the case, that you and he are partnered,
通力协作 共同调查
a task force of two, working it together.
操你 胖子
Fuck you, fat man.
并非原创 但简短有力 我喜欢你的说法
Not original, but succinct. I like your approach.
你指派我调查这个案子 已经羞辱过我一次
Y'all humiliate me once by dropping me into this thing,
现在又让Norris回来 再让我丢一次脸
and now you're gonna shame me again by bringing Norris back.
这是谋杀调查组 警探
This is Homicide, Detective.
而不是其他什么茶水间小组 大家都不在乎
This is not some boiler room unit where no one pays attention
他们干的活是不是够称得上警察
to whatever the fuck it is you call police work.
老大都知道我们的名字
The bosses? They know our names up here.
我并不喜欢他们
Now I didn't like it when they came to me
让我把Norris调走 但我还是调了
and told me to dump Norris, but dump him I did.
我也不喜欢现在为他们背黑锅
And it's not like I wanna carry water for them
假装他们从来没有指示我 做过这样的事情
now that they're pretending they never told me to do any such thing,
但我还是背了 而最后
but carry the water I will. And in the end,
等这个小组里的其他人 都抹上黑名翻不了身
when everyone else in this unit is buried and beshitted,
只有我这个警长还站着瞧你们
this detective sergeant will still be standing.
把故事编好了
So get the story straight:
Norris一直都是主要调查警官
Norris was always the primary,
而你正在协助他
and you are now assisting on an investigation
哪怕我们说话这会儿 调查仍在进行
which is progressing even as we speak.
副总警监知道这件事情吗
Does the colonel know about this?
他在医院里
He's in the hospital--
化疗没起作用
chemo didn't work.
半小时之后去楼上开新闻发布会
Press conference is upstairs in half an hour.
- 别迟到了 - 新闻发布会?
- So don't be late. - Press conference?
我不是故意嘲笑你的
I ain't mean to laugh at you none.
我知道听上去很疯狂  但我真没开玩笑
I know it sound crazy, but I ain't joking.
真的 Lex是个僵尸
For real, Lex a zombie.
Na他们说之前我就知道了
I knew it way before what Na' and them was saying.
听着 他们让我叫Lex去操场
Listen,they had me tell Lex to go up to the playground.
我告诉他去哪儿见几个妞
I told him to go up there and see some girl.
他就再也没有回去了
He ain't never come back down.
万一他们对我发火怎么办
So what they gonna do to me when they get mad at me?
Chris带他们去空地讲得通
It makes sense Chris taking them into the vacants--
他是要转化他们 还有什么你知道的
to change them. And you know what else?
他没有在干这样的事
That ain't what he doing--
Chris在空地
Chris in the vacants.
转化他们?
Changing them?
他没有转化他们 他杀掉了他们
He ain't changing them, he killing them.
就是这样 他们被杀掉了
That's all. They're getting killed.
你怎么知道的
How you know?
你别告诉别人
Can't tell nobody.
我见过
I seen it.
我见过他们带着一个男生 走到Calboun去
I seen them walk a boy up into one house over there on Calhoun.
你见过?
You seen that?
对
Yeah.
这是假的
That's just false.
Norris警探从没有 停止过对这个案子的调查
Detective Norris has been working in this case nonstop.
同时鉴于Greggs警探的毒品专长
And given her narcotics expertise,
她被指派去帮助
Detective Greggs was assigned to augment
而不是取代他
rather than to replace him.
但两天中这个部门内的消息人称...
But for two days sources inside the department were saying--
我也身处这个部门内  我现在告诉你这不是真的
I'm inside the department, and I'm telling you that's not true.
对刑事犯罪调查 我们不玩政治
We do not play politics with a criminal investigation.
那你对Gray议员的说法如何解释
And how do you explain Councilman Gray's allegations?
我觉得这个问题该去问Gray议员
I think you should ask Councilman Gray that question.
- 警察! 搜查令! - 去后门
- Police! Search warrant! - Take the back.
- 趴下 快! - 警察! 搜查令!
- On the ground, now! - Police! Search warrant!
两个人上去
Two upstairs.
- 别动! - 看看后间
- Don't move! - Check that backroom.
我说了 快蹲到地上
I said, get your ass on the ground.
- 蹲下! - 蹲下!
- Get down! - Get down!
- 这里是1300弄对么 - 不 这是1200
- This is the 1300 block, right? - No, this is the 12.
我们停对地方了吗
Are we on the right corner?
- 他们在这里藏毒品? - 窃听到的情报显示如此
- We had this as a stash house? - According to the wiretap.
多久前的情报?  他们经常搬来搬去的 要知道
How long ago? They move them around, you know.
逮捕令上的人一个都没抓到 标注的街角上只抓到几个小人物 长官
Zeroes on the warrants.Minor arrests on the designated corners, sir.
- 有人给他们通风报信! - 你说呢
- They were tipped! - You think?
所有的地方都扑空了 肯定是
For us to come up this empty at all these locations, it has to be.
那个混蛋Marlo觉得他比我们都聪明吗
This cocksucker Marlo thinks he's smarter than us?
他自作聪明罢了 警司 我要知道他平时都去哪儿
He is not. Sergeant, I want to know where he hangs.
你是说他私底下爱去哪儿吗
You mean like him personally?
他到处走 警官 从不停下
He moves around, Lieutenant. He floats.
但我看到他在Fulton后面的公园里坐着
But I have seen him in the concrete park behind Fulton.
- 在公园里? - 如果天气好 他会在那里
- In a park? - If the weather's right, he sits
找个长椅坐坐 接待别人
out there in some lawn chairs, holds court.
他派人在每条路上都守着
He's got people covering every approach
这样就没有人能偷偷摸到他身边 我猜他喜欢在室外谈话
so there's no creeping up on him. My guess is that he likes to talk outdoors
这样别人就窃听不到了
so no one can drop a microphone on him.
警司 我们现在该怎么办
Sergeant, what can we do with that?
我承认我是犯过一些错误 Burrel算是最严重的一个
I admit I've made some mistakes, Burrell being one of the biggest.
他再干十天就走人了
But he's got a job for about 10 more days.
初选之后 他就走人 相信我
After the primary, he's gone, believe me.
他那最后一个昏招 调走一名警探
And that last stunt-- pulling a detective.
- 你还指望什么呢 - 反正不是这样 不 不
- What'd you expect? - Not that-- huh-uh.
嘿 这胡闹和我一点关系都没有
Hey, I had nothing to do with that nonsense.
这可是睁着眼睛说瞎话 你告诉他把这个案子放慢下来的时候
Now, that's a straight-up lie. I was at that damn meeting when you told him,
- 我可是在场的 - 我不是那个意思
- "Slow the case down." - I didn't mean--
谁他妈知道你是什么意思 Clarence?
Who the hell knows what you mean anymore, Clarence?
瞧瞧这个
Look at this.
看啊!
Look at it!
你还向我保证过 保证啊 Clarence
You gave me your word on this-- your word, Clarence.
但你在Eunatta有优势的区 同她争夺选票
But here you are ticketed up with Eunetta in her best precincts
然后又在我家丫头Daniels最强势的地方 同她争锋夺势
and then ticketed up with my girl Daniels where she's running strong.
Odell 我第一次看到这个东西
Odell, this is the first I've seen this.
别这样 说不定是Eunetta的人搞的鬼
Come on, now! This is probably Eunetta's people pulling this shit.
上面还印着"人人为Royce"的官方戳印么
With a "Citizens for Royce" authority line?
看看你自己 Clarence 看看你自己
Eh, look at you, Clarence. Just look at you.
你都忘了你的议程 你都忘了自己的老本
You've forgotten your agenda. You've forgotten your base.
你觉得刮刮胡子
You think a shave
弄点Marcus Garvey 风格的宣传画 就能帮你度过难关么
and some Marcus Garvey posters are gonna get you over?
你觉得这样就能弥补你同每一个 房地产开发商眉来眼去么
Do you think that's gonna make up for jumping in bed with every damn developer?
你居然连Clay Davis都搞上了
Shit. You're even on Clay Davis's tit.
你别把气都撒在我身上 Odell
Now don't you go getting all self-righteous with me, Odell.
竞选需要花钱 你明明知道
Campaign runs on dollars-- you know it.
谁的钱? 那些每个月凑在你牌桌旁边
Whose dollars?! Those sons of bitches you got around your card table
喂着你小猫咪的贱人的钱吗 哦 没错
every month feeding your kitty? Oh, yeah,
这个我也知道 你...你的问题...
I know about that too. You-- trouble with you--
操你妈的 Clarence 你剩下的烂摊子我不管了
fuck you, Clarence. I'm gonna sit what's left of this one out.
- 我撒手不管了 - 撒手吧
- I'm gonna sit it out. - Sit it out.
- 初选怎么办 - 撒手了!
- The primary? - Sit it out!
Odell! Odell!
你他妈觉得自己是什么人物啊
Who the hell do you think you are, huh?
到了11月 我还是城里唯一的玩家!
Come November, I'm still gonna be the only game in town!
Odell 你现在背叛我 我绝不会忘记的!
Odell, turn your back on me now, I won't forget!
他不能走 我们需要他周二的组织
We can't afford this. We need his organization on Tuesday.
- 去追她啊! - 操他的
- Go after him! - Fuck that
狗日的假惺惺
holier-than-thou motherfucker!
Watkins代表 Watkins代表!
Delegate Watkins. Delegate Watkins!
等等 先生
Wait, sir.
我相信我们能解决这个问题的
I-I'm sure we can work this out.
你和市长再谈谈 能解决的
You and the mayor can talk this through.
接Rawls副局长 谢谢
Deputy Rawls, please.
是市政厅的Hoskins警长
It's Lieutenant Hoskins at the Hall.
你要利用墙上的那个洞 对吗
You're gonna use the hole in the wall, right?
对 我要在前面擦一点狗屎什么的
Yeah, I'm gonna rub some dogshit on the front of this thing.
我不想让别人碰它
I don't want nobody touching it.
好了吗
Got it?
再抬起来一点
You need to raise it a bit.
好了 就那里 行了
Yeah, that's good. Right there, that works.
- 我好像听到了什么 - 老鼠
- Thought I heard something. - Rats.
- 现在做什么 - 该走了
- How we doing? - We need to go.
他也不是什么个东西 一开始也不过是个恶心的家伙
He ain't nothing but a skanky-ass bitch to begin with.
而且 他以前是警察 你知道是什么样
And besides, he ex-police. So you know what that like.
我要去洗手间
I'm going to the ladies' room.
Bey 你得和他谈谈
Bey, you need to talk to him.
探视时间还有30分钟
Visiting hours end in 30 minutes.
- 探视时间... - 喂 老爸 你就别费口舌了
- Visiting hours... - Yo, Daddy, don't even go there,
你以前不是一直告诉我 你荒废了整个六年级
with you all the time telling me how you dropped out in the sixth grade,
然后同Avon和Stringer一起去了街角
went up on the corner with Avon and Stringer,
挣钱养家 告诉我 这段经历让你成为了男人...
earned cheese for the family, saying how it made you a man--
没错 没错 你没说错
All right, all right. You right.
还是不够狠啊 但我还是得说说
Can't throw rocks. But I'm just saying,
你知道你妈妈是什么样的脾气 大惊小怪的
you know how your mother be, with all the fussing.
你就装装样子给她看 你懂我的意思吗
Maybe you just need to slow it up. You know what I'm saying?
对了 你听说Marlo怎么整Bodie了吗
Yo, you heard how Marlo punked Bodie?
说他要是不来给他干活 就别想在街角混了
Said he either got to work for him or give up his corner.
你知道不 他就屈服了
Don't you know? His sorry ass buckled.
哦哦 那你就不会了吗
Oh-hh, you'd have gone about it different?
对 我会挺直了腰杆 就像你那样
Yeah, I'd have stood tall, like you.
拿着我的9毫米 操Chris一家
Got my nine-- fuck Chris and them.
听听你说的话 满股子热血
Listen to you, all spit and fire.
你一个人就担起这么多的事情
You'd have gone to the mattress all by your lonesome
同大半个西区的人作对
and went up against half of the West side.
你知道什么才是对的 这一点比什么都重要
You got it where it counts, and I respect that more than anything.
但现在的事不比从前
But shit out there now ain't like it was when we was coming up.
要是以前 像Marlo这样不安分的黑人
Back in the day, a punk nigger like Marlo steps out,
不守规矩 就会被人塞进后车厢
breaking the rules and shit, he find himself in the back of a car trunk
扔去Leakin公园 毫无疑问
on the way to Leakin Park. No doubt.
我们那路子是对的 说到就要做到
We did that shit right. Word was your bond.
大家都小心处事 知根知底
Man looked out for his own, knowing he in a family.
你懂我的意思么
Dig where I'm coming from?
但现在都乱套了
But today it's all fucked up.
这些台阶
These steps.
- 谢谢 亲爱的 - 现在可以了
- Thank you, baby. - You're good to go.
说 "Omar"
Say "Omar."
Omar
Omar.
没有吗
Nothing?
这条路两边我们都检查了
We checked both sides of the street
- 从这里到Monroe - 什么都没?
- from here up to Monroe. - Nothing?
除了下水道还是下水道
Nothing that don't belong in no sewer.
谢谢
Thanks.
还有什么别的主意吗
Other ideas?
兄弟 把那边那个黑人给我干掉
Blood, bump me off that nigger up the "skreet."
那栋房子里的狗日的?
Motherfucker in the "Bruick"?
就是她了
That be him. I be saying,
谁都不许从我的地盘上逃走
no motherfucker gonna run off with my "hairon."
哦 这真是太他妈精彩了
Oh, this is fucking great.
找人来读唇语 这熊孩子之前就这么玩过
Get somebody who reads lips, this motherfucker's history.
这合法吗 我是说  窃听他们的谈话内容?
Is this legal-- I mean, intercepting what they're saying?
别给我装傻子
Don't go Freamon on me.
糟糕 我要走了
Shit. I got to run.
嘿 兄弟 那我怎么办? 我已经待了一个早上了
Hey, man, what about some fucking relief? I been here all morning!
你听说了吗 他们在拍小电影
You heard? They making movies.
听说了 你想怎么演
Yeah. How you wanna play it?
我不知道 先去见见胖子吧
I ain't sure. Let's see the fat man.
其他事情进展如何
How'd the other thing turn out?
都很顺利
All good.
- 喂 - 怎么了
- Yo. - What up, boy?
- 如果你要的话 我有点Reeses - 不 兄弟
- If you want some, I got Reeses. - Nah, man.
你想不想赚一点外快? 5块钱?
You trying to make some real cheese? $5?
- 你要什么 - 我和Paul准备和Tiff来一炮
- What you need? - Me and Paul gonna get it on with Tiff.
帮我守着 别让D夫人瞧见了 你懂了吗
Keep an eye out. I don't want Mrs. D creeping up. Feel me?
我懂了 但还有些六年级学生 在等着我发特别订单
I feel you, but I got some sixth-graders waiting on a special order.
让他们等呗 我们又不是成天有空
Let them wait, man. It ain't like we gonna be all day.
好吧
All right.
不 夫人 上面写着 法官大人 已经让固体废料局
No, ma'am, it says right here-- His Honor had the Bureau of Solid Waste
沿着Tivoly指挥清扫了
conduct a clean sweep along Tivoly.
但他们还要六个月才会来
But it took six months before they showed up.
对 但人无完人
Well yeah, okay, but nobody's perfect.
但 听着 如果我不是真心相信
But hey, listen. I wouldn't be sitting here if I didn't believe
Clarence Royce是真的对这座城市 这里的人民好 我是不会留在这里的
Clarence Royce wasn't truly committed to this city and its people.
那我们社区的犯罪还没解决呐
What about the crime in our neighborhood?
我得承认 这是个好议题
I admit that's another good point.
但夫人 这话我只对你说 听你的声音
But, lady, between you and me, I can tell
你该是个黑人 你听我的声音也知道 我是个白人
from your voice you're black and you can tell from my voice I'm white.
那我得问你
So I gotta ask you,
你觉得为什么明明候选人中有白人
when do you think the last time a white man voted for a black man
但我这个白人却投票给黑人呢
when there was another white man in the race?
我不知道 但你绝对是很相信他
I don't know, but you must really believe in him.
对 这不正是我说的么  他就是最好的候选人了
Well, ain't that what I been saying? He's just the best candidate.
- 所以你会支持我的候选人吗 - 我会考虑的
- So you'll go with my man? - I'll think about it.
好的 太好了 打扰了
All right, that's great. Thank you for your time.
- 再见 - 好的
- Goodbye. - All right.
- 我正要去大厅 - 挺好的
- I have a hall pass. - Yeah, good for you.
- 我好了 - 干得不错
- Mine's down. - Attaboy.
你要找尸体嘛 Lester 这儿就有
You need bodies, Lester? Here you go.
我们的金童Lex身负 一张逮捕令和一个电报
We got a warrant and a teletype for my boy Lex.
不管是死是活 他都记录在案了
So dead or alive, he's on file.
除此之外 现在你该将你的智慧
And beyond that, it's time for you to shine
运用到更实在的谋杀案上了吧
that mighty intellect of yours on some real murders, hmm?
别老是臆想了
Give up the hypotheticals and shit.
我想也是
Yeah, I suppose.
这就是我关心的议题 犯罪 我完全明白你的意思
This is my issue-- crime,and I understand completely what you're saying.
如果你给我机会 我就有办法
And if you give me the opportunity, I will be able to do something to--
来帮助你 以及这个社区里的人
to help you out and, you know, other people in this neighborhood.
Ricks先生 打扰了
Mr. Ricks, thank you for your time
- 感谢你能听我说完 - 客气
- and for your attention. - No problem.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
真是厚脸皮 光天化日同敌人握手
Pretty brazen, shaking hands with the enemy in broad daylight.
- 这可不是什么Werner熟食店啊 - 当然不是
- Werner's Deli this isn't. - Definitely not.
我就猜想你在这里 议员 每家每户都走一遍
Though here you are, Councilman, leaving no door unopened.
鞋底是我们的秘密武器
Shoe leather-- our secret weapon.
你让我大吃一惊  你
You surprised me. You've made this a horse race.
那你有什么好的理由来说服我 你不是碰巧来这儿遇到我们?
So uh, what makes me think you didn't just happen by and find us here?
Watkins同市长闹翻了
Watkins is breaking with the mayor.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
我就是知道 我为市长背黑锅 是因为我不得不这么做 议员
I know. I've carried the mayor's water because I had to, Councilman.
我希望这个城市能够注入新鲜血液
I'd love to see some new blood in this city.
我也希望能有机会 来改变警局的现状
And I'd love the chance to do the right thing for this police department for a change.
等他拐弯再动
Wait until he turns the corner.
Gilmore大街 Watkins的办公室
District office for Watkins--Gilmore Street.
别管红灯了
And fuck them red lights, man.
这儿你可见不到什么黑帮
Not a place you expect to find any gangsters--
或者是警察的
police, for that matter.
- 听说你这儿有我没听说过的消息 - 早就告诉你了
- Heard you knew something I didn't. - Told you before--
我办事得耳听八方
I make it my business to keep an ear to the ground.
我办事就是真的办事
I make it my business to do business.
我们是办事 还是聊天呢
We doing business, or are we just talking?
如果是聊天 我就走了
And if it's talk, I'm walk.
我听说守牌局的那伙人 对他们的薪水不太满意
I heard the people pulling security at the card game weren't too keen on their wages.
我想 他们要找到弥补的办法
I figured it was only a matter of time before they
也不过是时间问题
found a way to get their due compensation.
你为什么没有告诉我
And you didn't think to tell me?
吃一堑长一智
A man learns best when he get burned.
我怎么知道你不是瞎编的呢
How do I know you ain't making this shit up?
你是不知道 到处都会出事
You don't. Things happen on the street.
而证据很难找到
Proof is hard to come by.
来啊 拆开看看
Go ahead, open it.
私底下 其实证据到处都是
Off the street,there's all kind of proof.
他们决定周五的时候执行计划
They planning on executing those Friday--
是冲着选举去的 我猜
time it with the election, I guess,
表现自己尽职尽力  收拾这个城市 打倒关键人物
show they doing their job, cleaning up the city,taking down a kingpin.
- 你怎么知道这个的 - 刚和你说了
- How did you come by this? - Told you before--
我耳听八方呢
I keep my ear to the ground.
- 你准备怎么办 - 也许什么都不做
- What are you gonna do with it? - Maybe nothing.
Charlie和我们可没什么关系
Charlie's not part of the co-op.
也许我能给他通风报信 赚点外快
Or maybe I tip him for a fee.
你觉得坐拥金山的人 会为自由付出什么代价?
What do you think a man with a whole lot of money would pay for his freedom?
要知道 最近
You know, lately
我发现有人想要给我拍点东西
I come to find out someone trying to take pictures of me.
东西?
Pictures?
录像
Video.
你旅行的时候 有没有听说和我有关的事情
You heard anything about me through your travels?
没什么事懒得听
Had no incentive to listen.
你现在听说了
You do now.
在初选时作壁上观是一件事
It's one thing to sit out the primary.
而同Clarence Royce对着干是另一回事
It's another for me to turn on Clarence Royce.
- 假设一下 - 如果我真的要跳槽
- Granted. - And if I did jump,
我干嘛不去支持Tony Gray?
why not land behind Tony Gray?
至少他是我这边的人
At least he's from my side of the tracks.
Tony赢不了 但我能
Tony can't win. I can.
听着 事实是 不论我开出什么价位 市长都能提出同样甚至两倍的价码
Look, the truth is,whatever I can do for you, the mayor can match or double.
我的管理层都是草根出生
I have a pretty good grass-roots organization,
但绝对不比上他那么有钱
but nothing even close to his kind of money.
而我 你让我跟谁的票 我就跟谁的票
Now, I'll ticket up with anyone you want me to.
我知道你想让Daniels赢下11区 还有Stokes赢下第10区
I know you want Daniels in the 11th and Stokes in the 10th.
只要你觉得不行 我就不去搅局
I'll keep away from any tickets you think I might harm.
我知道对于这个城市来说 我不是每个人理想中的人选
I know I'm not everyone's idea of a bargain on your side of town.
但现在 初选还有一周
But right now,a week from the primary,
Royce和我都需要你
the fact is,Royce and I both need you.
但在选举之后 他不再需要你 而我却不会改变
After the election, the equation changes for him but not for me.
在这个黑人为主的城市里 我作为一个白人市长 如果我要做出什么改变
I'm a white mayor in a majority-black city, and if I'm gonna do anything--
是的 代表  我当真是想要治理好这个城市
and, Delegate, I am so serious about fixing this city--
我必须得到民众的拥护
I'm gonna have to govern by consensus.
而如果你支持我 光是因为我需要这一点
And if you support me, you will have a voice within my administration
你就会成为我管理层中举足轻重的一员
simply because I'm gonna need it.
Clarence给我看的上次投票结果 他上涨了7个点
Last poll that Clarence showed me, he was up by seven points.
胡扯 我才掉了不到4个点
Bullshit. I'm within four.
- 你不需要那个 - 我知道
- You won't be needing that. - I know.
- 这里? - 对 这里
- Here? - Yeah, here.
糟糕
Dag.
喂 把手电关了 灯泡会变热的
Yo, turn it off-- the bulb might have got too hot.
或者电池会不够用
Or the battery's dying.
我们该回去了
We should go back.
- 喂 兄弟 这里好臭 - 以前不臭
- Yo, man, it stinks, man. - Ain't like it was.
瞧 他不动了
See he ain't move.
对
Yeah.
头发上还沾着血
Blood still stuck to his hair.
- 他死了吗 - 他死了
- He dead? - He dead.
Lex也死了
Lex too?
他死了 他们都死了 感觉好点了吗
He dead. They all is. Feel better?
Donut错了
Donut wrong, yo.
没什么死了和没死一样
Ain't no special dead.
死了就是死了
There's just dead.